# **Sulakshana Chakraborty**

#### **Graduate Student**

Tech-savvy and analytical professional with 3 years of experience in the IT consulting industry with a background in Electrical and Electronics Engineering. Curious and always willing to expand my knowledge. Currently pursuing a master's degree in Data Science and Machine Learning at UCL. Skilled in machine learning techniques for various applications such as natural language processing, computer vision and recommendation system.

sulakshana.ch2014@gmail.com



https://github.com/SulakshanaChakraborty



Camden, London, NW1 9HZ



in https://www.linkedin.com/in/sulakshanachakraborty-a4b9681a0/

+44 7765720314

# **Experience**

### ZS ASSOCIATES, NEW DELHI

Was part of the technology solutions track, implementing BI/tech solutions for pharma clients to ease sales analytics, account profiling, HR planning etc.

### **Business Technology Solutions Associate Consultant**

Dec 2020 - Jun 2021

- Led the ETL team in building an end-to-end data warehousing pipeline using AWS and PySpark for weekly sales reports on Tableau dashboards.
- Further went on to manage the dev-ops post the production release, orchestrated weekly data refreshes using Airflow. Was responsible for providing client support.
- Managed workstreams working in different time zones, ensured smooth functioning of the technical aspects of the project delivery, and efficiently worked in fast-paced, intensive environments

#### **Business Technology Analyst**

May 2018 - Dec 2020

- Implemented business workflow solutions using inhouse application development software to support clients with critical sales planning process and HR management.
- Involved in every aspect of the software development lifecycle (SDLC) of projects which includes technical design, build and testing. Also worked closely with the business stakeholders during requirements gathering phase.
- Worked on developing analytics pipelines, transforming raw data into information that gives valuable insights.

# **Technical Expertise**

Languages/Libraries: Python (PyTorch, TensorFlow, Scikit-Learn, NumPy, Pandas), Scala (PySpark), SQL, R

**Software/Tools:** Amazon Web Services, Dell Boomi, Alteryx, Microsoft Suite (Access, Excel), Linux, Git, Airflow

## **Certification & Publications**

Certification: • IBM Data Science Professional Certificate

Deep Learning Specialization by DeepLearning.Al

**Publication:** Implementation of Facial Recognition for Home Security Systems, published in International

Journal of Emerging Trends (IJET), 2018

# **Education**

### MSC DATA SCIENCE AND MACHINE LEARNING

University College London, Sep 2021 – Current

#### Modules undertaken:

Statistical Natural Language Processing Information Retrieval and Data Mining Intro to Deep Learning Machine Vision Intro to Statistical Data Science Applied Machine Learning Intro to Machine Learning AI for Sustainable Development

### B. TECH ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS

Vellore Institute of Technology, Jun 2014 – April 2018

**CGPA**: 8.67